<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>networking - Tag - Parth Goswami</title>
        <link>https://www.parthgoswami.com/tags/networking/</link>
        <description>networking - Tag - Parth Goswami</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>parthifs.g@gmail.com (Parth Goswami)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>parthifs.g@gmail.com (Parth Goswami)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.parthgoswami.com/tags/networking/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Certified Calico Operator: Level1</title>
    <link>https://www.parthgoswami.com/certified-calico-operator/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Parth Goswami</author>
    <guid>https://www.parthgoswami.com/certified-calico-operator/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/ccol1/banner.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>In this article, I will share my experience in becoming a Certified Calico Operator: Level 1. Most of the information is available on the course portal and Calico’s webpages. I&rsquo;ve made an effort to compile all the essential details about the course and exam in one location, and I hope it will be helpful to you.
What is Project Calico? Project Calico is an open-source project with an active development and user community.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Configuring a custom VPC</title>
    <link>https://www.parthgoswami.com/configuring_vpc/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Shreya Dhange and Parth Goswami</author>
    <guid>https://www.parthgoswami.com/configuring_vpc/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In the previous article, we learned what VPC is, how does it work and what are its benefits. AWS provides a pre-configured to launch our instances, however, the best practice is to create your own custom VPC per your requirements and organization&rsquo;s network and security policies and launch your instances in the custom VPC. In this article, we will discuss how to configure your own custom VPC.
Leaving services running in cloud computing can escalate your bill quickly, hence, it is equally important to understand how to delete the resources once you are done using it.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How does VPC work?</title>
    <link>https://www.parthgoswami.com/decoding_vpc/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Shreya Dhange and Parth Goswami</author>
    <guid>https://www.parthgoswami.com/decoding_vpc/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[If you start from the bare metal layer and go right up until the container layer through virtualization, base OS and the container engine, you would notice that networking runs throughout the stack.
Networking is the backbone of any infrastructure. Hence, understanding the networking concepts becomes very important and if we are talking about cloud computing, it becomes ever more important.
In this article, I will be discussing how networking works in the cloud computing.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
