<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>How-to - Tag - Parth&#39;s Blog - Parth Goswami</title>
        <link>https://www.parthgoswami.com/tags/how-to/</link>
        <description>How-to - Tag - Parth&#39;s Blog - Parth Goswami</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>parthifs.g@gmail.com (Parth Goswami)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>parthifs.g@gmail.com (Parth Goswami)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.parthgoswami.com/tags/how-to/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>What is DNS?</title>
    <link>https://www.parthgoswami.com/dns/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Gaurav Kale</author>
    <guid>https://www.parthgoswami.com/dns/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/visiting_authors/gaurav_kale/dns/dns_1.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Domain Name System With over 8 billion cellphones worldwide (not including other devices), it is hard to correctly recall everyone&rsquo;s names and contact information. Because of this, the Domain Name System—or more precisely, the Phone Directory for IP Addresses—was introduced. However, due to the memory limitations of the human brain, we are unable to recall all of these billions of IP addresses. In order to make it easier to remember names, we began referring to these IP addresses by names, which are simply the website names that we type into the address bar of a browser.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Deploying Jenkins slave using docker containers</title>
    <link>https://www.parthgoswami.com/jenkins_docker_master_slave/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Nihal Shah</author>
    <guid>https://www.parthgoswami.com/jenkins_docker_master_slave/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[While exploring Jenkins, I came across a usecase wherein I wanted to make use of Jenkins slave to build some of my jobs. So after exploring I found out a way wherein we can deploy Jenkins slave as containers. Once the job is complete, the containers will be destroyed, thus releasing the resources. This removes the dependency to have extra VM&rsquo;s or need for more storage to accomodate the jobs.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Certified Calico Operator: Level1</title>
    <link>https://www.parthgoswami.com/certified-calico-operator/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Parth Goswami</author>
    <guid>https://www.parthgoswami.com/certified-calico-operator/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/ccol1/banner.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>In this article, I will share my experience in becoming a Certified Calico Operator: Level 1. Most of the information is available on the course portal and Calico’s webpages. I&rsquo;ve made an effort to compile all the essential details about the course and exam in one location, and I hope it will be helpful to you.
What is Project Calico? Project Calico is an open-source project with an active development and user community.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Getting started with Jupyter Notebooks</title>
    <link>https://www.parthgoswami.com/jupyternotebooks/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Parth Goswami</author>
    <guid>https://www.parthgoswami.com/jupyternotebooks/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/jupyternotebook/jupyternotebook.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>I started exploring and using Jupyter Notebook earlier this year for a project based on opensource enablement, licensing and operate first. This is the first time ever I was working with a notebook and apparently had to start from sratch right from understanding how it works, how it needs to be installed and finally how it is to be pushed to a repo and publish the work.
In the process of exploring the tool, I went throught quite a handful of articles and videos.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Docker containers using Ansible on AWS</title>
    <link>https://www.parthgoswami.com/docker_containters_ansibleaws/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Vrinda Hegde and Siya Amonkar</author>
    <guid>https://www.parthgoswami.com/docker_containters_ansibleaws/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Ansible is an open-source configuration management and deployment tool.
Below are the steps to run docker container on AWS EC2 instances using Ansible playbook.
Create AWS EC2 instances (master and slave) Update the security group of slave exposing port 8080 Install Ansible on master Install python on slave Update /etc/ansible/hosts on master with the slave IP Create a dockerfile which will be used to create customized image Create an ansible playbook with detailed tasks Execute the ansible playbook Check if the docker container is running successfully on the slave machine Install Ansible on master machine: Execute the below commands to install Ansible on the master machine:]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Managing Windows Server from Red Hat Server using Ansible on AWS EC2</title>
    <link>https://www.parthgoswami.com/ansible_sd/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Shreya Dhange</author>
    <guid>https://www.parthgoswami.com/ansible_sd/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/ansible_sd/ansible_windows1.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Pinging Windows server from Linux server where Windows server is the target node and Red Hat is the ansible server]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Dockerizing LAMP Stack Application</title>
    <link>https://www.parthgoswami.com/dockerizing_lamp_stack_app/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Vrinda Hegde</author>
    <guid>https://www.parthgoswami.com/dockerizing_lamp_stack_app/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Let us create a dockerfile for deploying the application. In this dockerfile we will use ubuntu image as the base image and then install apache and php above it. Then we will create a MYSQL container which will be connected to our application.
Below is the Dockerfile snippet: 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47 48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 # Dockerfile for LAMP Stack installation # Ubuntu 18.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Amazon EKS: A managed Kubernetes service by AWS</title>
    <link>https://www.parthgoswami.com/amazoneks/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Parth Goswami</author>
    <guid>https://www.parthgoswami.com/amazoneks/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Kubernetes won the race to become the de-facto container orchestration engine. Ever since, a lot of companies are coming up with their own version of container orchestration based on top of Kubernetes, while, some other companies are developing tools and products to complete the Kubernetes in the orchestration space.
Having said that, the top three cloud provides, have come up with their own version of managed Kubernetes offerings:
Microsoft Azure offers the Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS) AWS offers the Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (EKS) Google Cloud offers the Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE) What is Amazon EKS?]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How to get started on AWS</title>
    <link>https://www.parthgoswami.com/aws_for_beginners/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Parth Goswami</author>
    <guid>https://www.parthgoswami.com/aws_for_beginners/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Nope! This is article is not about what AWS is, how it works and what are its services, rather it talks about AWS and how to get started with it being a complete beginner. I am working on AWS for more than 5+ years now and have taught professionally for 2 years, hence, I understand how overwhelming it might get for a beginner to figure out how to start studying AWS.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Invoke AWS Lambda from Slack</title>
    <link>https://www.parthgoswami.com/lambda_slack/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Siya Amonkar and Varshareddykumbham</author>
    <guid>https://www.parthgoswami.com/lambda_slack/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[AWS Lambda is a compute service that lets you run code without provisioning or managing servers. Lambda runs your code only when needed and scales automatically, from a few requests per day to thousands per second. AWS Lambda in our task is invoked using the API Gateway.
Slack is a channel-based messaging platform. With Slack, people can work together more effectively, connect all their software tools and services, and find the information they need to do their best work — all within a secure, enterprise-grade environment.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
